We are reading a very short statement
scripture from Habacook. Uh tell your
neighbor Habachuk
this month. We've been talking about
vision and about the theme vision as we
unveil it. And this particular scripture
is a key scripture in what we have been
talking about. And so I want to read
verse 1 to4. It says we must pay most
careful attention therefore
uh not Hebrews, sorry, excuse me,
Habakok. They took me to Hebrews,
Habakok. And [clears throat] by the way,
Habachuk on a light note is the prophet
who used to cook habs. Um, so we are
reading.
It's to help you remember uh this these
prophets. Some some of their names can
be a challenge. It says, "I will stand
at my watch and station myself on the
ramparts.
I will look to see what he will say to
me and what answer I am to give to this
complaint."
Then the Lord replied, "Write down the
revelation
and make it plain on tablets so that a
herald may run with it. For the
revelation awaits an appointed time.
It speaks of the end and will not prove
false. Though it linger, wait for it. It
will certainly come and will not delay.
See, the enemy is puffed up. His desires
are not upright. But the righteous
person will live by his faithfulness.
Amen.
>> This is God's word. and God's people say
>> amen.
>> Uh please be seated in God's presence.
Shall we pray?
Father, thank you so much.
This is the last Sunday of the month of
January. Indeed, this month has run
quite fast, but we want to thank you
that you have been a faithful God. And
Lord, as we have unveiled the theme
vision for the year, we thank you that
God, you always give us a word. And
Lord, we thank you that your vision
always comes to pass, that you are a God
who speaks and you make things happen.
And so, Father, as I speak and break
your word to our spirits and our hearts,
may the Holy Spirit continue to make
this vision clear. And may the name of
the Lord continue to be lifted up in our
midst
here in this country and across the
globe. Thank you for the lives you're
touching and the lives you're shifting
because of the word of God that is going
out. All glory goes back to you. So
father, open our hearts, open our ears
to receive your word because we have
prayed in Jesus name. And God's people
say
>> amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
God is a God who speaks to us in
visions.
I'm saying God is a God who speaks in
I'm saying God speaks in visions. Now
vision is a language. It's just like
when you're speaking your your
vernacular language whether it is lua lu
kik kikuyu and all those things is a
language
it's a means of communication it's a
means of expression and god who we do
not see speaks and speaks in dreams
speaks in visions now for the prophets
of old as they spoke they began as they
received the visions God told them to
write the vision down and they began to
write those things and that's why we
have the Bible and most of it was given
through visions and through dreams.
You know, sometimes when I read the the
five books of Moses, for example, when
you're reading Genesis,
um, and and you're reading Exhading
Exodus and you're reading the five books
and especially Genesis,
um, and you and Moses was not there when
those things were happening. And you
wonder how did Moses get to know things
about Abraham and things like that. And
of course we know that some of these
things are passed on by
fathers giving saying that's giving the
stories to their sons and then it goes
on like that. But one of the amazing
things is this that God is able to bring
the things of the past to a prophet and
really dictate some of these things. Uh
sometimes many of you wonder how does
pastor Ambrose uh keep preaching uh for
all these years and he always has a
message and I want to tell you this I
don't go reading dictionaries and
reading all those things to get a
message or going to the internet to find
a message. Hello.
I ask God. I ask God and God gives the
word. Hallelujah.
God gives
>> the word. God is amazing. He gives the
word.
And so
God gives vision. Let me read this verse
in Job. Job. Job uh I believe it is Job
verse 15. Let me see if it is it is the
right one.
Job 35
um 33. Let's see 33 because I wasn't
sure. 33. Job 33 verse 15 and 16
it says in a dream in a vision of the
night when deep sleep falls on people as
they slumber in their beds he may speak
in their ears and terrify them with
warnings. Now that's an interesting
verse. Now let me read it in the New
King James because sometimes you think
oh that we're going to have nightmares
or serious nightmares. So let me read
this in the New King James. In a dream
in a vision of the night when deep sleep
falls upon men while slumbering on their
beds. Uh then he opens the ears of men
and seals the instruction. In other
words, he instructs them. He speaks to
them. Now, of course, uh some dreams
basically don't come to God and
especially after you have eaten a lot
before you go to sleep, you dream crazy
things. But I want you to know that God
speaks, he speaks. And when he speaks in
a vision, because today what I'm talking
about is this, the vision that speaks
because the vision will speak. God will
bring to pass what he says in a vision
or in his word. It will come to pass.
Sometimes it comes to pass in very
interesting ways but at the end of the
day it will come to pass. So let me read
Habak one more time V vers verse two and
three. Habak
very quickly. Habacook
in the New King James Version. Let me
read it in that version. Um very
quickly. Okay. It says verse two. Uh
give me verse two. Then the Lord
answered me and said, "Write the vision
and make it plain on tablets that he may
run who reads it. For the vision is yet
for an appointed time." And that's the
part I'm talking about. But at the end
it will speak. At the end it will speak.
God will speak. This vision will come to
pass. This thing we are talking about
the year of the Lord's uplifted door.
Uplifted open door. God is saying, "I
have opened a door for you." You may not
believe it now, but let me tell you this
because I've declared it. It's going to
happen. And that is why it is important
for you to read the vision so that you
may know what is this that God wants to
make to pass. What does God want to
release in my life to make to pass? What
should I do? And how is this vision that
God is saying going to come to pass?
You know when when Mary uh when Jesus
was born and of course during that time
when when Mary saw the vision of the
angel and the angel said you shall have
a child and this child will be the
savior of the world. Mary may not fully
have understood what that was all about.
And so you can imagine when Jesus was
growing up and Mary is looking at this
child and Mary is remembering what the
angel said about Jesus when Jesus was
was going to pre-unit.
Hello. And and he remembered this this
this Jesus. This is what was said. And
it was not just spoken by the angel.
They also listened to Anna who had
prophesied and Simeon who had prophesied
about this child. And she wondered what
what this is a special child. What will
happen to this child? What? And she
pondered those things. But later when
Jesus was on the cross being crucified,
she began to remember this is what God
had said. And as Jesus was dying because
this was her first born and Jesus was on
that cross and she's feeling she's
mourning. She's in grief but she's
remembering this is what the angel said
that the vision would come to pass. It
would speak at the end and it was not a
vision to bring hopelessness. It was a
vision to bring hope. She encouraged
herself and she said this is what the
Lord said. And I want to tell you this.
The reason why God speaks to us is so
that in the future we will know that God
had spoken and nothing is taking him by
surprise. The Bible says, "I know the
plans I have for you, says the Lord.
Plans for welfare, not for evil to give
you a future and a hope.
God speaks." So what do we do when God
has spoken and nothing seems to be
happening?
So those are the three things I'm going
to say right now. Number one, wait for
it. Very simple. There are three
statements. Wait for it. Number two,
believe for it. And number three, listen
for it.
Now, waiting is not a very interesting
part there. But this is not a waiting uh
hopelessly.
Now these days of cell phones have
changed a lot of things
uh in terms of dating, in terms of
passing information, in terms of just
communication.
There was a time in Kenya when there
were no cell phones
and the only way of communication were
to enter a certain booth,
a red booth
and you communicate. Now dating was very
interesting because if you needed to get
somebody in a certain place
uh and you need to meet it was not easy
but this is what people did it became
very innovative
in the city of Nairobi near a place
called Kenko
there was a clock
so if you're going to meet you tell
whoever you're dating let us meet at the
Now, knowing the situations in the city,
of course, you'd come there early in
time, especially if you're the guy,
you'd come in time. All who would come
first?
>> The guy.
Hello. And you stand at the clock.
Interesting enough, you found many other
guys
around the clock. And you know the buses
used to come around there because the
buses would turn and stop there. And let
me tell you this, the waiting was not
easy.
People would wait and every and you wait
and you know you people would not wait
casually. You are not just sitting there
waiting and just waiting. No, every bus
that is passing
you are looking. In other words, you
waited with expectation.
That's what I'm talking about. The Bible
says they that wait upon the Lord shall
renew their strength. So this waiting is
not a hopeless waiting. It is a waiting
that God said something and I'm waiting
with it with expectation.
>> God is going to do something.
That's why every time we look into
another month, we're saying I want to
see what God is going to do. And people
would wait and the waiting was not for 2
minutes.
There was a time people would wait from
11:00 Saturday
and that person would not show up until
3:00 in the afternoon. But nobody gave
up.
Hallelujah.
Because after Kencom and the person
would come, you would go to a place
called Ambassador.
Hallelujah. There was a cafe there.
Thank you Jesus. And you have your date.
But you waited and your dream came true.
Let me tell you this. What God has been
telling us through the month of January,
let us wait for it expectantly
because it's going to happen.
>> I'm saying it is going to happen
>> in Jesus name. It's going to happen.
It's going to happen. Wait for it. Wait
for it. Let me read these verses in
Psalm Psalms 27. It's a very interesting
psalm and I want to read pick it up from
around verse uh let's see around verse
let me pick it from verse 10. The Bible
says this but it's a good psalm
especially when you're waiting on the
Lord. It says though my father and
mother forsake me. So this guy is going
through a very difficult time and he's
saying some things can happen that may
not really work out for us. Though my
father and mother forsake me, the Lord
will do what? Will receive me. And then
he says, "Teach me your way, Lord. Lead
me in a straight path because of my
oppressors. Do not turn me over to the
desire of my foes, for false witnesses
rise up against me, sprouting malicious
accusations." You're going through a
very difficult time. I remain confident
of this. Now, this is the the the
statement of faith. I remain confident
of this. I will see the goodness of the
Lord in the land of the living. And then
it says in verse 14, wait for the Lord.
Be strong and take heart and wait for
the Lord. Amen.
>> Wait for the Lord. Things may go
haywire. Uh in fact, the previous
verses, you know, talk about going
through very rough waters, but guess
what? Whatever it happens, if God said
it, God will make it happen. Trust him.
He will come through for you. I'm saying
he'll come through for you.
>> Some of the things we were praying for
yesterday, you know, and sometimes are
very challenging. There's a lady who
came to me and said, "Pastor Ambrose,
pray for my my my son, and my son has
not spoken for for since he was born."
And I I asked her, "How how old is your
son?" He says, "He's 9 years old."
Never spoken.
Never spoken. One of the word that God
released yesterday is this that there
are children with autism who have never
spoken and God is loosing their tongues.
>> God is loosing their tongues.
>> Jesus name. You know, and I I'm
repeating that to say God who said it
will make it happen.
>> God will make it happen. Uh I remember
one time during uh during again a
revival season uh not revival season an
anointing service um there was the while
the message was ongoing and again the
word of prophecy was spoken that God was
loosening the tongue of somebody there
was a lady who was online watching
and uh Don Gishan had invited them to
watch uh the the proceedings and this
girl was much older
you know, something traumatic had
happened to her and she shut down and
she could not talk for a long time. Now
she's listening to the to the message
and she hears the word saying that your
tongue is being loosed
immediately
online with her mother she started
talking.
Let me tell you this, God is an amazing
God. God is a powerful God and I I
believe that lady will come back with a
testimony because it's very challenging
for having a child who is not
communicating and let me tell you this
God also feels it when he has children
who don't talk to him.
Let me talk to some people on this site.
Yanni Yanni, you got saved and and and
you don't talk to God. And God is
saying, "Please talk to me and say,
"Mama, say
and you're just saying,
let me tell you this. God loves it when
he hears your voice. When he hears you
talk, even when you don't talk much, uh
sometimes you don't have to pray like a
prayer warrior. Sometimes you listen to
Don Timo praying and you're saying, "Oh,
God
and you're a man because men are very
challenged especially because their
wives are the ones who do most of their
prayers and every time in your house if
you want anybody to pray, he says,
"Mama, pray for food."
So mama prays for food. So for a long
time, mama is the one who prays for
food. And one time there was a gentleman
one time he was in a boardroom and he
had never prayed. Every prayer was
prayed by his children or his wife. Then
he's in a boardroom. He's a CEO
and as the secretary who happened to be
a Christian said, "Uh, excuse me, sir.
Why don't you lead us in a word of
prayer?" He took him by offside. He got
shocked. But anyway, he said since the
se has been asked and he doesn't have to
be to be to be embarrassed, he just
stood up and he prayed the best way he
prayed. And this is what he said.
Father, for the food we are about to
take, bless it. and he sat down
because for a long time that's the the
only prayer he had heard. So if you're
sitting next to a man just just look at
that man and tell that man it is okay.
You don't have to pray like a prayer
warriorh
and don't have to pray like donimo
because when Timo prays he says father
yes lord
and you know you want to start praying
like that can you imagine in your house
you know you start praying like that at
father
your wife starts laughing you know she's
she's wondering just what happened to my
husband.
So just pray normal prayers and say Lord
I really don't know how to pray but I'm
just thanking you for my wife and for my
children and thanking you for the day in
Jesus name. Amen.
And God gets excited. He talked.
He spoke and God gets excited. But let
me tell you this. There are some things
that have delayed in your life and
sometimes you begin to give up and you
wonder will God ever come through? Now,
let me read you this verse in Numbers
23:1 19 because God, you wait because
this vision will speak. I'm talking to
somebody. This vision will speak.
>> I'm talking to somebody. This vision
will speak.
>> It speaks at the end. It says this, "God
is not human." Let me read it in the New
King James Version here. And this is I
really like this verse because I keep
repeating it many times. It says God is
not a man that he should
>> lie nor a son of man that he should
repent.
Has he said and will he not
>> do or has he spoken and will he not make
it
>> good? You will still see the goodness of
the Lord
>> in the land
>> of the living.
>> Wait up. Tell your neighbor, wait.
Tell your neighbor, be expectant.
>> Be expectant
>> and God will come through.
>> And God will come through.
>> Amen.
>> We really want to appreciate the pastors
who came from Mombasa.
Please stand. These pastors, some of our
pastors who came from Mombasa and these
these are some of the leaders of the
Lone the they from Leoni, but they also
leaders in that um community. The cost
>> co cost
Coast clergy community.
Come on, let's appreciate them.
Amen.
And and the lady, Pastor Farah, you are
the treasurer. You're the treasurer.
Money bags
were you know, wait for it. The We went
there and we had a fantastic time.
Uh please be seated.
The church we preached in was a church
that hosted us where we actually did our
preaching. My brother Justin,
this pastor, we preached in his church
and we had a very good time in Loni
and when we went there and we had this
convention later when we were talking in
fact it is it is in that church we
started talking about the open door and
that the doors is open and we preached
and preached later when I was talking to
this pastor he later told me that that
church had gone through a terrorist
attack in his church and he was in that
church when there's terrorist came and
how many people died?
Six on the spot.
This pastor went through a very
traumatic time just going through this.
And he he just tells me that it was one
of the craziest times of his life
and he wondered whether God really knew
about him and whether he had a plan for
him.
But later while we were there and God
was really reaching out and speaking and
doing amazing things,
um he began to tell me
because we came,
God comforted him.
God strengthened him.
And sometimes you may go through certain
things that are so traumatic and you
wonder whether the God you believed in,
the God you served is really the one who
allowed this to happen. Let me tell you
this. God does not cause trouble.
He does not come to steal and kill and
destroy. The devil is the one who comes
to steal, kill, and destroy. But Jesus
came that we may have life and have it
abundantly. But let me tell you this,
between who God is and the challenges of
life and the promises that will come
true, sometimes it takes a season of
waiting,
but stay there because this God will
turn your situation around. Amen.
>> And my brother, we are glad we came to
your church and we are glad we came and
these ministers received us very well
and we thank God for that. Amen. We
thank God for that. We celebrate you and
we thank God for all the pastors in Loni
Mo.
Please be seated. Let's appreciate him.
Tell your neighbor, wait with
expectation.
>> Secondly, believe for it. Tell your
neighbor, "Believe for it."
>> Believe for it.
>> Uh tell tell the other neighbor who
ignored you, "Believe for it."
>> Believe for it.
>> Amen.
>> As I go there, let me say it one more
time.
Don't ever give up on God
no matter what is happening. Because
even in this season where mental issues
and mental challenges are are so are so
prof there are so many. Never reach a
stage where you give up on God. God
loves you. God is a good God. Tell your
neighbor, God is not a bad God.
>> God is not a bad
>> Tell your neighbor, God is a good God.
>> God is a good God.
>> And then tell them you will still see
the goodness of the Lord.
>> You will still see the goodness of the
Lord
>> in the land of the living.
Yes. Yes, you will. And so, believe for
it. Believe for this vision. This vision
will come to pass. In other words, trust
in the Lord. Let me read this parable
that Jesus spoke in the book of Luke
concerning a certain lady in Luke
chapter 18. I read from verse one very
quickly. Believe for it even when things
are very challenging. The Bible says
this. Then Jesus told his disciples a
parable to show them that they should
always pray and not give up. He said in
a certain town there was a judge who
neither feared God nor cared that people
what people thought. And there was a
widow. So take a picture. There's a
judge. He doesn't care about things.
Then there's a widow helpless alone. She
cannot defend for herself. And there was
a widow in that town
[clears throat] who kept coming to him
with a plea, grant me justice against my
adversary.
For some time, he [clears throat]
refused. But finally, he said to
himself, "Even though I don't fear God
or care what people think, yet because
this widow keeps bothering me. I I
wonder what kind of woman that was.
I don't know if she was from Meu, but
sometimes some things can be very
challenging.
But you know, there are people who can
be persistent.
>> Persistent. Yi, they don't give up. Huh?
Yet because this widow keeps doing what?
>> Bothering me. I will see that she gets
justice so that she won't eventually
come and
wow
this judge was bad news because she was
there every morning she's sitting there
waiting y the judge has not even arrived
in the office she's there give me
justice give me justice now Jesus is
giving this parable now do you think it
was just a story maybe those are things
that were happening at that time and
Jesus is thinking about that and saying
I I want to share
a truth through this story. And then now
listen, Jesus is trying to apply this to
us. And the Lord said, listen to what
the unjust judge says.
And will not God bring about justice for
his chosen ones? Now remember this time
it is God and his chosen ones. The other
one is an unjust judge and a widow. a
very contrasting picture and this time
it is God and his chosen ones and he's
trying to contrast these two. He says,
"And will not God bring about justice
for his chosen ones who cry out to him
how
>> day and night? Will he keep putting them
off?" Try to answer that. Will he do
that?
>> Can God do that? Can God be compared to
this unjust judge? No. But sometimes
when things are stretched and all that,
we actually begin to think God is an
unjust
judge. That is not right. He's he's
oppressing me. And that's what Job felt
one time. Job just said, "God, I wish I
was not born.
I wish I was still born. This thing is
too much for me." But listen to what Jes
Jesus is trying to say. And this is what
I'm praying for today. says this, no
matter what happens, believe for it.
>> Believe. Trust God. Uh go back, go back,
go back to that verse. Then I pick it
with verse 8. And will not God bring
about justice? I'm talking to somebody
here. God will come through for you.
>> Amen.
>> I'm saying again, God will come through
for you.
>> And will not God bring about justice for
his chosen ones who cry out to him day
and night? Will he keep putting them
off? No. Then the Bible says this, I
tell you, I tell you, all right. Um, I
tell you, he will see that they get
justice and how
>> quickly
>> quickly. And talking about Job who went
through a very difficult time and
sometimes people think that Job went
through a rough time for a long time.
Uh, some people say actually it was near
it was about 9 months.
Hello. But those nine months can seem
very long. And Job went through this
thing wondering how will God come
through. And God was just saying and
saying, "Hey, believe for it. Believe
for it. Believe for it."
You remember remember the story of
Gyrus.
Gyrus, not not your neighbor at home.
[snorts]
Okay? And came and tell Jesus, "My
daughter is just about to die." And
Jesus said, "Okay, let's go and heal
her." And the Bible says when they were
just about to go, a woman interrupted
that journey. Women,
I don't know how Jarus felt. The woman
comes, this woman who came through the
crowd, came through the crowd and then
touches Jesus' garment and she's healed.
And Jesus stops to talk to her. Can you
imagine? It is an emergency. It is an
emergency, Gyrus. This is an emergency.
And Jesus stops. What do you think Gyrus
thought about Jesus?
So Jesus stops and begins to talk to
this lady. Maybe it took about 20
minutes as she talked to this lady and
said, Jesus is saying, "Who touched me?"
And nobody seems to be answering
quickly. And then the woman says, "I
touched you." And Jesus says, "Your
faith has made you whole."
But at that minute as this woman goes,
news comes to Gyrus that don't bother
the master. Your daughter is what?
>> Is dead. Jesus knew Jyus was going to
collapse. And Jesus said, "Hey Gyrus,
just believe."
What I told you earlier, keep believing
that. Don't believe the circumstances.
Don't believe the situations. Believe
me, believe me, believe. Keep believing
it. And Jarus is wondering, "But the
daughter is dead." He says, "No, no, no.
just keep believing it. Keep believing
it. And so they left her, they left that
place and went to her place. And of
course people are already mourning. And
of course in those places uh people tend
to bury the same day. Hello. You die.
You they cry cry. And so he finding
everybody crying uh crying everywhere
weeping. And Jesus is saying, "Hey,
don't weep. Uh the child is sleeping.
Because Jesus tends to see things from a
very different perspective.
And the people who are weeping start
laughing.
Hello.
It reminds me of a western funeral
service. Uh the people from Kisumu.
Thank you Jesus.
Okay. They are crying, crying, crying
and then they start laughing. You know,
emotions change like this. And that's
that's what happens sometimes. Zuko
western
people arrive and they have never even
been in that if they're not even part of
that place but the moment they enter
they get
and they're saying all kinds of things
after they've sat down they ask where is
tea
[laughter] you And
between the weeping and the tea just
what happened but tell your neighbor it
is normal those sides.
Thank you Jesus. It's normal those
sides.
There are some things that are so
normal. That's the place where they talk
to even the dead and the person is dead.
They're in the coffin but they're
talking to the guy. Sa
why did you die yesterday? How could you
just have died? By the way, you have my
my my my my money. You should not have
died after that. Hey.
And some of you come and say, "Hey, he's
sweating. Can we can we can we remove
the sweat?" Tell your neighbor, it is
normal those sides.
But the berieved gyrus is wondering,
"Will God do anything? Will God do
anything?" Jesus goes, touches the girl
and says, "Talithum."
and the girl wakes up and the mother
comes takes that child. A sudden shift,
I'm talking to somebody today. A sudden
shift
>> is about to happen.
>> Amen.
>> Wait for it. Believe for it. Amen.
>> For Job, as I prepare to finish my
message,
tell your neighbor, there is a job 42
coming.
Tell your other neighbor, "There's a job
42 coming your way."
>> Tell them, "I hope you believe that."
>> Amen.
>> Let me read for you that verse in Job 42
as we get to pray. But I tell your
neighbor, "Wait for it.
>> Wait for it.
>> Believe for it.
>> God will come through for you.
>> God will come through for you."
>> Amen. Amen.
>> And I like this verse. Let me read those
verses in Job. The Bible says this in
verse 10 of Job 42:10 because that is
somebody's portion.
It says this after Job had prayed. After
he did what?
>> Prayed. After Job had prayed for his
friends, the Lord restored his fortunes
and gave him twice as much as he had
before. Look at the next verse. All his
brothers and sisters and everyone who
had known him before came. Now let me
tell you this. They came that Job
chapter 1 to verse chapter 41.
Nobody came. Everybody had abandoned.
You don't hear of a brother or a sister.
The only thing you hear is of a wife who
said curse God and die. Job was
finished.
But when God turned his fortunes,
God also shifted the attitude of the
family.
>> And not just some of his brothers, all
his brothers and sisters and everyone
who had known him before came and ate
with him in his house. They comforted
and consoled him over all the trouble
the Lord had brought on him, which is
not true.
Okay, that's how they thought. But in
reality, the Lord had not done that. Who
did it?
>> The devil. Okay, give me that verse.
Comforted and consoled him. All right.
Uh all his brothers and sisters and
everyone who had known him before came
and ate with him in his house. They
comforted and consoled him over all the
trouble the Lord had brought on him. And
each one gave him a piece of silver
and a gold ring. Let me tell you this,
there are fortunes coming your way.
>> There are people who hate you now, but
they will bless you tomorrow.
>> Amen.
>> I'm saying there are people who hate you
now, but they will bless you tomorrow.
>> Somebody missed that. There are people
who hate you now, but they will bless
you tomorrow.
>> And of course, I can also say this.
There are people you hate now.
Thank you Jesus.
>> But you will bless them.
>> Hallelujah.
>> God can shift your situation. And then
the Bible says the Lord blessed the
latter part of Job's life more than the
former part. He had 14,000 sheep, 6,000
camels, a thousand yoke of oxen, and a
thousand donkeys. And he also had seven
sons and three daughters. The first
daughter he named Jamaima, the second
Kazia, and the third Karen Hapuk.
Nowhere in all the land were there found
women
as beautiful as Job's daughters, and
their father granted them an inheritance
along with their brothers.
>> This is the God we serve. Amen.
>> Come on, somebody.
This is the God we serve.
On this side, a very dark picture.
But through waiting
and believing
on this side, a totally different story.
>> Wait for it, believe for it. And
finally,
[clears throat]
>> what's the third thing? Listen,
>> listen for it. And I won't stay here a
lot because I just wanted to say pay
attention to the vision. Don't give up
on it. So, uh, let me read this while
you're standing. I'm reading first kings
19 11-13. This is the time when Elijah
was so depressed because of a threat uh
from a woman.
I'm saying
[laughter]
go thank God he created women. God is a
good God. Uh uh when they are on your
side my friend life is good.
When they are on the wrong side
[laughter]
but at the end of the day they were
created for a purpose.
>> But this particular one really gave
Elijah a difficult time. threatened him.
Jezebel, you remember that story? And so
he ran. He wanted to kill himself. He
wanted to just die.
And so God decides to meet him. And the
Bible says, "The Lord said, "Go out and
stand on a mountain in the presence of
the Lord, for the Lord is about to pass
by." Then a great and a powerful wind
tore the mountains. You know, there was
a lot of sound apart and shattered the
rocks before the Lord. But the Lord was
not in the wind. After the wind, there
was an earthquake.
But the Lord was not in the earthquake.
After the earthquake came a fire, there
was drama. But the Lord was not in the
fire. And after the fire came what?
>> A gentle whisper.
Sometimes you just need to listen.
Things may be going haywire around you,
but God is not in that chaos. God wants
to speak very gently because God needed
to speak to this man gently in a very
soft voice. Even though he was shattered
and broken, God wanted to speak to him
and comfort him. When Elijah heard, so
let me read that back. Go back to verse
12. The Bible says this, "After the
earthquake came a fire, but the Lord was
not in the fire. And of the fire came a
gentle whisper. When Elijah heard it, he
pulled his cloak over his face and went
out and stood at the mouth of the cave.
Then a voice said to him, "What are you
doing here Elijah?" Now remember it is a
whisper. God is not upset. God is not
angry. And you know sometimes like
Elijah wanted to commit suicide. He
wanted to die. And sometimes people who
have sometimes attempted suicide feel
very guilty that they actually even
attempted suicide and they even think
that God is against them. Let me tell
you this, God is very gentle.
>> God knows that what has pushed you to
the brink. He knows and so he'll be very
gentle. He replied. Now this is now his
reply. This is Elijah.
Now he's giving his reason. I have been
very zealous for the Lord God Almighty.
The Israelites have done what? Have
rejected your covenant. Torn down your
altars and put your prophets to death
with the sword. I am the only one
left. And now
they're trying to kill me too.
Rukini depression down there. The Lord
softly started saying said to him, "Go
back the way you came and go to the
desert of Damascus. When you get there,
anoint Hazile, king of Aram. Your job is
not over.
Go anoint. Yes, you're down, but go
anoint." Uh also anoint Jahu son of
Nimshi king of Israel and anoint Alicia
son of Shaf from from Abel Mayha to
succeed you as a prophet because I will
finish with you. And guess what? I will
take you to heaven on the chariots of
fire.
>> I will still bless you.
And it required for Elijah to listen
because God spoke softly
and gently. For some of us, we don't
need a shouting God. We just need a
whispering God, a gentle God. That is
why pay attention when God is speaking.
The vision will speak. But wait for it,
believe for it, listen for it. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Why don't you give God a big hand? Bless
his name. Amen.
Though the vision may tar,
it will still come to pass. It is
appointed time will still come. Amen.
>> Doesn't matter the circumstances that
you're facing. Our God who said he's not
a man that he should lie. He's not a son
of man that he should change his mind.
Will still bring to pass what he said.
Whether through a vision, whether
through a dream, or whether through a
direct spoken word to you, this year is
your year of rising.
>> I'm talking to somebody. It's your year
of rising.
It's your year of rising.
It may be dark here like Job,
but celebration is coming.
>> Amen.
Here
it doesn't tell us a lot about the sons
and whether he had daughters.
But here
the most beautiful women,
sleigh queens of old,
property,
donkeys, wealth.
What the devil took away,
God restored
double.
>> May God restore double.
Double.
Amen.
What COVID took away,
what COVID destroyed,
what COVID destroyed. And some of us
have not recovered to this day. God is
not a man that you should lie.
This God who prospered you
in 2018, 2018 and 2019 and all that was
lost during co. God is not a man that he
should lie. He's not a son of man that
he should change his mind. What he told
you that day has not stopped
in 2024.
Your fortunes will be restored.
>> Amen.
>> Your fortunes will be restored.
multiplying,
flourishing.
We serve an awesome God. And so Ambrose
has come here today to tell you this.
This God is still alive.
>> Still alive.
>> And your children's children and your
children's children will prosper in the
land.
>> Will prosper in the land. Oh, I'm
telling you, somebody better give God a
big hand.
Somebody better give God a big hand. Oh,
I love God. I bless God. This is the
year of the uplifted open door. The
vision will speak.
>> Though it tar,
>> it will speak.
>> The devil is a liar, but God is the
truth.
>> And I choose the truth
>> rather than the lie of God.
Take a moment as you pray. Just thank
God.
Oh my God.
Talk to God and thank him. Yes,
you may be in a dark space
but light
is rising.
Oh God, [music]
thank you Jesus.
Thank you for my brothers and sisters
and even those watching online.
The vision will speak. [music]
It is for an appointed time.
And though it tries, wait for it,
believe for it,
listen for it.
God is a good God.
God is a good God. Father, we love you.
and we bless you and we praise you.
Yes.
[music]
Amen.
Father, I want to pray for your people
right now.
And I believe
joy morning may last for the night but
joy comes in the morning. And for some
people here we are declaring your joy
has come this morning.
>> Your joy has come this morning.
>> May God who promised
bring it to pass.
>> He has not forgotten you. He has
remembered you through his word today.
So
wait expectantly.
Believe with a lot of trust.
Listen
and pay attention. The vision will still
speak.
It will still come to pass. People said,
>> "Amen." Come on, give God a big hand.
Amen.
Are you glad you came?
>> Yes.
>> Did you learn something?
>> Which part did you learn?
>> Which one?
>> Wait.
>> Wait for it. Uh, some of you the only
part you heard is the beautiful women.
Uh, in fact, you're planning to take all
those names
and
name your children. But let me tell you
this, God will do you good.
>> God is going to do you good.
>> Amen.
>> Yeah. When I think about God doing us
good, I think of Pastor Sammy. Uh, when
last year, was it before the anointing
service, he had a stroke,
a very severe stroke.
landed at Empisha Hospital.
He was yesterday here for the anointing
service.
>> Amen.
Isn't God good?
>> This time next year, you'll have
something to shout about.
>> You'll have something to shout about.
Amen.
So look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor, "You're looking good."
>> You're looking good.
>> Better than when the service started.
>> And now
>> you will shine.
>> You will shine.
>> God has given you the word.
>> God has given you the word. [music]
>> Look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor, "Surely goodness
>> Surely goodness
>> and mercy
>> shall follow you
>> all the days of your life
>> all the days of your life.
>> And you shall dwell in the house of the
Lord.
Forever
>> forever
>> and ever.
>> And there's nothing the devil can do
about it.
>> There's nothing the devil can do.
>> You are blessed.
>> To be a blessing.
>> to be a blessing.
>> You're favored.
>> You are favored.
>> To be favorable.
>> You are lifted.
>> To lift others.
>> In Jesus name.
>> in Jesus name.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.